Finding Aid for the James, Meadows and Howard, Architectural Records: Airport Renovation and County Stadium Projects, 1963-1978 (bulk 1968-1974)
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
James, Meadows and Howard, Records: Airport Renovation and County Stadium Projects
1963 - 1978
Mss. B80-3
James, Meadows and Howard
5 boxes (2.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, specifications, notes, contracts and architectural plans for the renovation of the East Terminal building of the Greater Buffalo International Airport and for the construction of Erie County Stadium (Rich Stadium) in Orchard Park, N.Y.
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
James, Meadows and Howard, Records: Airport Renovation and County Stadium Projects, 1963-1978 are open for research.
Administrative Information
Acquisition Information
Meadows, Rufus W.; gift; 1980/01/17; 80-22
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Historical Note
James, Meadows, & Howard worked as Associate Architects for both projects documented in this collection. In the airport project, James, Meadows & Howard was an associate of Howard, Needles, Tammen & Bergendoff; in the stadium project, it was an associate of Finch-Heery.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, specifications, notes, contracts and architectural plans for the renovation of the East Terminal building of the Greater Buffalo International Airport and for the construction of Erie County Stadium (Rich Stadium) in Orchard Park, N.Y.
See also C77-5.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series:
I. Greater Buffalo International Airport, East Terminal Renovation Project
II. Erie County Stadium (Rich Stadium) Project, Orchard Park, New York.
Container List
- Greater Buffalo International Airport, East Terminal Renovation Project, 1968-1971, I.
  - East Terminal description and specifications, undated (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Field measures, surveys, notes, undated (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Preliminary estimates, architectural, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Contract, undated (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Miscellaneous file, undated (Box-folder 1.5)
  - McKaig, Rupley & Bahler, undated (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Specifications-N.F.T.A, undated (Box-folder 1.7)
  - Requests for payment,, undated (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Contract-I, undated (Box-folder 1.9)
  - Contract-II, undated (Box-folder 1.10)
  - Contract: James, Meadows & Howard, 1970 (Box-folder 1.11)
  - John W. Cowper Company, undated (Box-folder 2.1)
  - Wilson, Klaes, Brucker and Worden, undated (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Wilson, Klaes, Bruker Associates, undated (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Conveyor details, undated (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Estimating information, Spring 1971 (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Howard, Needles, Tammen and Bergendoff, 1970 (Box-folder 2.6)
- Erie County Stadium (Rich Stadium) Project, Orchard Park, New York, 1972-1974, undated, II.
  See also C77-5 addition.
  - Stadium Ticket and Seating Information, undated (Box-folder 2.7)
  - Stadium Sketch Tracings, undated (Box-folder 2.8)
  - David M. Berg, Inc. (Box-folder 2.9)
  - Site Work (plans), undated (Box-folder 2.10)
  - Stadium Leaks, undated (Box-folder 3.1)
  - Preliminary Investigations, undated (Box-folder 3.2)
  - Empire Soils Investigations, Inc. (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Agreements for Joint Venture, Heery and Heery, Finch Alexander Barnes Rothschild and Paschal, and James Meadows and Howard, undated (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Expansion Joint, undated (Box-folder 3.6)
  - Buffalo Bills/Robert Lusting, undated (Box-folder 3.7)
  - Blakeley-Daniels, undated (Box-folder 3.8)
  - Erie County Department of Public Works, undated (Box-folder 3.9)
  - John W. Cowper Company I, undated (Box-folder 3.10)
  - John W. Cowper Company II, undated (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Job Meetings, undated (Box-folder 4.2)
  - General Correspondence, undated (Box-folder 4.3)
  - Wheelchair Access Plans, undated (Box-folder 4.4)
  - Bid Documents for Erie County Stadium, Concession for Vending Foods, Beverages and Tobacco, undated (Box 4, Volume 1)
  - Buffalo Bills Facilities, Erie County Stadium, Kivett and Myers, Architects and Planners, October 1972 (Box 4, Volume 2)
  - Revision of Volume 2, December 1972 (Box 4, Volume 3)
  - Specifications for Erie County Stadium, Finch-Heery and James, Meadows and Howard, February 1972 (Box 4, Volume 4)
  - Stadium Originals, undated (Box 5, Volume 1)
  - Stadium Addendum, Office Copy, undated (Box 5, Volume 2)
  - Engineer's Project Diary/Erie County Stadium Project, March 29, 1972-November 20, 1973 (Box 1-4, Volume 1)
  - Engineer's Project Diary/Erie County Stadium Project, September 15, 1972-April 26, 1974 (Box 1-4, Volume 2)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Buffalo History Museum
Subject Terms
Finch-Heery (Firm); Greater Buffalo International Airport; Rich Stadium (Orchard Park, N.Y.); Stadiums--New York (State)--Erie County; Architects--New York (State)--Buffalo; Howard, Needles, Tammen & Bergendoff
Genre Terms
Architectural drawings (visual works)